Belinda Gorman

very experienced school counselor in all aspects of counseling and the high school admissions process

New York, NY - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Belinda-Gorman/5db92613c4de790d

School Counselor with 12 years of experience working with middle school students, utilizing a broad range of counseling techniques to cultivate student success with social, emotional and academic achievement. Highly experienced with the New York Public, Independent and Parochial High School process. Experienced working with high school students and the college process

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

High School Counselor

Mott Hall II - New York, NY -

September 2013 to Present

New York

Expertise with the New York City Public, Independent and Parochial High School Process

Provide individualized expertise and assistance to parents and students (grades 6-8) with applications, letters of recommendation, transcripts, school reports, financial aid, scholarships and more

Advise Parents and Students one on one with high school process

Provide academic counseling for failing students

Coordinator of prestigious enrichment programs (TEAK, The Oliver's Scholars, The

Breakthrough Program, Prep for Prep for 9, Liberty Leads at Bank Street, A Better Chance)

Devise various forms and tools for students to utilize throughout the high school process to increase confidence and success with completion of applications

Conduct student and parent high school workshops and mock interviews

Coordinator of 504 forms: Process, approve and conduct planning interviews for students with Individualized Education Plans

School Counselor

Mott Hall II - New York, NY -

September 2004 to June 2013

Provided individual and group counseling and academic advisement to mandated and at risk students

Collaborated with administrators, student based support team, teachers, parents and students to meet educational, social and emotional objectives

Created goals for individualized education plans

Member of Pupil Personnel Team (assessed students for academic intervention and provided case management)

Assisted pupil personnel secretary with monitoring attendance, parent outreach and related issues

Prepared and provided grades 6-8 with one on one advisement with public, independent and parochial high school process

Coordinated (high school related) prestigious academic enrichment programs (TEAK, The

Oliver's Scholars, The Breakthrough Program, Prep for Prep for 9, The Liberty Leads Program at Bank Street, A Better Chance)

Wrote letters of recommendation

Devised various forms and tools to increase student confidence and success with completion of applications and enrichment programs

Conducted student and parent high school workshops and mock interviews

504 Coordinator

Made referrals for community based organizations and outside intervention and support services.

EDUCATION

MS Ed School Counselor

Hunter College - New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Communications/Education

Hunter College - New York, NY

SKILLS

Excellent Communication Skills, Very Experienced with all Department of Education Systems (10+ years)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

School Counselor

September 2006 to Present

Permanent Certification as a licensed School Counselor

GROUPS

American Counseling Association

September 2004 to Present

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Fluent in Spanish